SANSRIT PAUDEL

<u>2sansrit@gmail.com</u> | +977 9866334933 https://www.linkedin.com/in/sansrit-paudel/

INTRODUCTION

Inquisitive, energetic computer Engineer specialist with a strong foundation in math, programming logic and leadership. My passion is centered in Artificial Intelligence and robotics. I want to discover more about the medical robotics and reinforcement learning for autonomous navigation. My goal is to grow as a person and as a professional, every day.

EDUCATION

Kathmandu University, Dulikhel, Nepal

August 2017 – March 2022

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering

CGPA: 3.43 / 4.0

National School of Science and Technology (NIST), Lainchour, Kathmandu

June 2014 - August 2016

High school (physical sciences)

percentage: 73.60%

EXPERIENCE

Salesforce, Kathmandu, Nepal

Janurary 2022 – March 2020

Software Developer Intern

- Worked on developing CRM technology.
- Used SQL, Apex, and JavaScript to develop CRM technology.
- Facilitated collaboration between teams with GitHub best practices.

RIGHTE, Lalitpur, Nepal

April 2022 – Present

Software Engineer

- Worked on Developing Web and Mobile Application.
- Used React and Flutter to develop tech guided composting experience.
- Designed and conducted research experiments to test theories for improved performance.

PROJECTS

EnSat: A miniature version of an environmental satellite with embedded microcontrollers and sensors for clustering real time environmental data and the data modeled and visualized graphically. The data is stored in MongoDB database and represented in the GUI built in React. (Got selected for MongoDB Student Spotlights).

NLP Based Research Paper topic Classification: A Natural Language Processing based project that enable to ease finding and selecting suitable academic conference.

RoboQ: An efficient autonomous maze solving robot, solves mazes that finds and traverse the shortest path.

Sathi Kaha: A mobile application to track real time transportation services and created online payment system with RF embedded chips, built using Node.js, SQL, C++, React Native, Raspberry Pi, Arduino.

Cubes: An IOT project that aids tech guided composting experience especially designed to bring change on psychological and behavioral expects of composting.

CAMPUS INVOLVEMENT

Executive Member at Kathmandu University Robotics Club

- Worked on with learning and creating different robots, commenced with line following robot to maze solving robot.
- Organized 1st National level Can-Sat, Competition where 200+ students were trained to develop their own mini satellite and competition was organized.

Microsoft Student Partner

- Organized different workshops and webinars, collaborating with personnel from Microsoft. Ai gaming
- Started MSP Nepal Livestreams in YouTube, to teach various skills to students via virtual medium during 2020 pandemic lockdown.

Kathmandu University Computer Club

- Member of editorial team for annual technical magazine of the club, IT Express.
- Community Representative for the Club.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: JavaScript, Python, C++, Dart Libraries and Frameworks: Google Colab, Pandas,

PyTorch, Matplotlib, React, Node.js, Qt.

Technical Skills: MySQL, MongoDB, Azure, Raspberry pi, Arduino.

Languages: English, Nepali.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

IT Meet December 2020

 Design and documentation coordinator for IT MEET 2021, annual Technological festival of Kathmandu University.

International Youth Conference on Science, Technology and Innovation

October 2019

Volunteered for Project demonstration in national level science exhibition.

HONORS AND AWARDS

World Finalist, Microsoft Imagine Cup 2021

March 2021

• Our team *Virtual Radiologist* were in Top 12 in Microsoft Imagine Cup 2021 World Finals, out of the tens of thousands of students from 163 countries. We were in Top 3 teams in Earth Category.

Winner, Regional Tech Camp for Good Governance 2020.

February 2021

 Won 1st prize (\$7000) with the Winning IoT Project (CUBES), a smart bin and mobile app for solid waste management, out of 9 Finalist Country teams from South Asia, at the Regional Tech Camp for Good Governance 2020 co-organized by U.S. Embassy, Nepal and Kathmandu Living Labs.

Project (EnSat) got Featured by MongoDB.

February 2020

MongoDB is one of the most popular NoSQL database and widely adopted by industries.

Winner, Project Competition in LOCUS 2020

January 2020

 Won the Project Competition under Sustainable Development Goals Category (Sustainable Cities and Communities) in LOCUS 2020, National Tech Festival.

Beta Microsoft Student Ambassador.

Accessed to Microsoft resources and expert to build community, lead, learn and share.

Best Paper Award on Wildlife Conservation Nepal (WCN's) Conference for Young Nepali Scientist. December 2019

• Won 1st prize on "Youth for Smart Solutions 3" WCN's Conference for Young Nepali Scientists is an event organized by Nepal Prakriti Pathshala (NPP) in collaboration with WCN and Danish Forestry Extension (DFE).

PUBLICATIONS

[1] S. Paudel, S. Shrestha, A. Khanal, A. Adhikari and A. Shrestha, "Environmental Satellite to Monitor Real-Time Environmental Parameter Changes in Response to Increased Climate Action," in *International Astronautical Federation (IAF)*, Paris, 2022.